Guide to the Diskin Clay papers, 1962-2014 UA.29.02.0248
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Diskin Clay papers
1962-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Clay, Diskin
UA.29.02.0248
18 Linear Feet 14 boxes
Diskin Clay was on the Classics faculty at Duke University from 1990 to 2008. This collection of his professional papers includes correspondence, writings, teaching files, and research materials. Topics include Greek literature, especially poetry; Greek philosophy; and archaeology in Greece; specific topics relate to Oenanda, an ancient Greek city in Turkey, to the writings of Xenophon, Diogenes, and the poetry of Archilocus. There are also many slides of Greece, as well as from Italy and Paris, France, taken during research and archaeology trips.
Arrangement
Arranged in original order as received, in loose topical groups.
Biographical / Historical
Diskin William Thomas Clay (1938-2014) was on the faculty of the Classics Department at Duke University. He earned his BA in Literature from Reed College, in Portland, Oregon (1960) and his MA and PhD in Classical Studies from the University of Washington in Seattle (1967). He began his career at Reed University. After several teaching appointments, he joined the Duke faculty in 1990 and served as the R.J.R. Nabisco Distinguished Professor of Classical Studies until his retirement in 2008. He passed away in Durham, N.C., June 2014.
[Source: Adapted from obituary at Legacy.com, accessed May 4, 2020]
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. Optical disk requires reformatting for access.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Diskin Clay papers were received as a gift by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2014 and 2015.
Scope and Contents
The professional papers of classics professor Diskin Clay include correspondence, writings, teaching files, and research materials. Topics include Greek literature, especially poetry; Greek philosophy; and archaeology in Greece; specific topics relate to Oenanda, an ancient Greek city in Turkey, to the writings of Xenophon, Diogenes, and the poetry of Archilocus.
Also included in the collection are many slides of Greece, as well as from Italy and Paris, France, taken during research and archaeology trips. Clay's writings are also present in the form of short papers and drafts of longer works. There is one CD-ROM.
Archaeology -- Study and teaching; Classical literature -- Study and teaching; Duke University -- Faculty; Greek literature -- Study and teaching; Greek philosophy -- Study and teaching; Durham (N.C.); Greece -- Photographs; Optical disks; Photographs; Posters; Slides (photographs)
- Accession UA.2014-0060
  - Slides: Italy and Paris (Box 1)
  - Files: Lectures, conferences, JHU, Duke, clippings, photos, CVs (Box 2)
  - Slides: Greece, Cyprus, Paros (Box 3)
  - Slides: Paros, Delphi, Oinoanda, Survival of Apollo II; travel journals (Box 4)
  - Correspondence; files on Diogenes of Oenoanda (Box 5)
  - Slides: Italy and Greece (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, circa 1970s (Box 7)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Photos: Paros and miscellaneous negatives (Box 10)
  - Master's thesis, files of Clay's writings (Box 11)
  - Oversize portfolio with photos, maps, drawings, posters (Box 12)
- Accession UA.2015-0061
  - Liberty Fund materials (Box 13)
  - Unfoldered images (Box 13)
  - Cult of Archilochos: many folders on images (Box 13)
  - One Failing of Old Age (Box 13)
  - Lucretius and his Reader (Box 13)
  - Some Verse Epistles of Catullus (Box 13)
  - The Proem of Parmenides' Poem (Box 13)
  - Moonlighting (Box 13)
  - Epigraphica (Box 13)
  - Scripta: Louis Robert (Box 13)
  - Ai Khanoum (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Inscriptiones Scythiae (Box 13)
  - Greek numismatics (Box 13)
  - Oenoanda (Box 13)
  - The Artemis Archive: Magnesia Photographs (Box 13)
  - Die Inschiften Von Magnesia (Box 13)
  - Magnesia (Box 13)
  - C. Vibius Salutaris (Box 13)
  - Berezan (Box 13)
  - Alumni trip to Greece (Box 13)
  - Epicurean Seminar: Wurzburg, October 1998 (Box 13)
  - Xenophon: Memorabilia (Box 13)
  - Plato: Apology (Box 13)
  - Xenophon: Apology (Box 13)
  - The Trojan Women of Euripedes (Box 13)
  - Greek 201 (Box 13)
  - Unfoldered writings (Box 14)
  - Paros, October 2005 (Box 14)
  - Oenoanda: Alan Hall (Box 14)
  - Oenoanda: A proposed excavation (Box 14)
  - Oenoanda: M. F. Smith (Box 14)
  - Materials from Oenoanda (Box 14)
  - Loose correspondence (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Loose teaching materials (2 folders, 1 binder) (Box 14)
  - Archilochos: images (Box 14)
  - Archilochos: CDs and Negatives (Box 14)
  - Archilochos: Fr. 2 West (Box 14)
  - ZPE Archilochos (Box 14)
  - Additional Archilochos materials (Box 14)